《纳尼亚传奇3: 黎明踏浪号》
(祖国需要你 来参军吧)
Are you sure you're eighteen?
你真的是十八岁吗
Why? Do I look older?
怎么了,我看上去更老吗
(艾伯塔)
- Alberta Scrubb? - It's a typographical error.
- 艾伯塔·斯卡布  - 写错了
It is suppose to be Albert A. Scrubb.
应该是艾伯特·A·斯卡布
Edmund,
埃德蒙
you are suppose to be helping me with the groceries.
说好陪我去杂货店的
Better luck next time, eh, squirt?
小朋友,下次好运
Squirt? He barely had 2 years on me!
小朋友,他顶多比我大两岁
I am a king. I've fought wars and I've led armies.
我可是国王,带过兵打过仗
Not in this world.
不是在这个世界
Yeah, instead I'm stuck here.
是啊,我现在反而被困在这儿
Doing battles with Eustace Clarence Scrubb.
和尤斯提·克劳伦斯·斯卡布吵架
If anyone so deserve a name.
他可真是名不符实
What are you doing?
你在干什么
Nothing. Come on then.
没事,走吧
Dear Diary.
亲爱的日记
It is now day 253
我万恶的表哥埃德蒙和表姐露西
since my wretched cousins Edmund and Lucy invaded our house.
入侵我们家已经有二百五十三天了
Not sure how much long I can cope living with them...
不知道我还能撑多久
having to share my things.
我不想和他们分享我的东西
If only one could treat relatives like one who treat insects,
要是对待亲戚能像对昆虫一样
all my problems would be solved.
那所有的麻烦都解决了
I could simply put them in a jar,
直接把他们关在罐子里
- pin them to my wall? - I'm home!
- 或钉在墙上  - 我回来了
Hello?
有人吗
Note to self.
小贴士
Investigate legal ramifications of impaling relatives.
查找刺穿亲戚的法律后果
And that concludes the war news from the western front.
最后是西线战事新闻
Hello, Uncle Harold.
哈罗德姨父好
I've tried to find some carrots
我本想买点胡萝卜的
but all they had were turnips again.
但又只有白萝卜了
Should I start making soup?
我现在煲汤吗
Aunt Alberta is on her way home.
艾伯塔姨妈在回来路上了
- Uncle Harold? - Father.
- 哈罗德姨父  - 爸爸
Edmund making faces at you.
埃德蒙在对你做鬼脸
Why, you little...
你这个小坏蛋
Father, he's going to hit me.
爸爸,他要来打我了
Edmund look, it's from Susan.
埃德蒙快看,苏珊来信了
I do wish you were here with us.
真希望你们也在这儿
It is such an adventure.
这儿的生活真像冒险
But nothing like our times in Narnia.
但比不上纳尼亚
America is very exciting.
美国真令人兴奋
Except we never see father. He works so very hard.
除了总看不到老爸这点,他工作太忙了
I was invited to the British consul's tea party this week
一位海军长官邀请我这周参加
by a naval officer.
英国领事馆的茶话会
Who happens to be very handsome. I think he fancies me.
他很帅,我觉得他喜欢我
It seems that the Germans
德国似乎现在
have made the crossing difficult right now.
战况急转直下
Time are hard.
时局动荡
Mother hopes you both won't mind
母亲希望你们不介意
another few months in Cambridge.
在剑桥多待几个月
Another few months? How will we survive?
再待几个月,我们怎么熬得下去
You're lucky. At least you've got your own room.
你幸运多了,起码你有自己的房间
I'm stuck with mullet mouth.
我和那个讨厌鬼住一起
Susan and Peter are the lucky ones.
苏珊和彼德才幸运
- Off on adventures. - Yeah.
- 又开始历险了  - 是啊
They are the olders we are the youngest.
谁让他们比我们大呢
We don't matter as much.
别计较太多
Do you think I look anything like Susan?
你觉得我哪儿长得像苏珊吗
Lucy, have you seen this ship before?
露西,你之前看过这船吗
Yes, it's very Narnian looking isn't it?
是的,很有纳尼亚的风格是吧
Yeah. Just another reminder that we're here not there.
是的,又在提醒我们这里不是纳尼亚
There once was two orphans who wasted their time
从前有两个孤儿总浪费时间
believing in Narnian nursery rhyme.
相信着纳尼亚童谣
- Please let me hit him! - No.
- 让我揍他吧  - 不
- Don't you ever knock? - It's my house.
- 你不会敲门吗  - 这是我家
I do as I please.
我想干什么就干什么
You're just guests.
你们只是客人
What's so fascinating about that picture anyway?
这幅画有什么吸引人的
It's hideous.
丑死了
You won't see it from the outside of the door.
局外人是看不懂的
Edmund look, looks like the water is actually moving.
埃德蒙快看,水好像真的在动
What rubbish, see?
净说瞎话,看到没
That's what happens when
这就是魔幻小说
you read all those fancy little novels and fairy tales of yours.
和童话看多了的结果
There once was a boy called Eustace,
从前有个男孩叫尤斯提
who read books full of facts that were useless.
看的书里净是些毫无用处的事实
People who read fairy tales are always the
那些看童话的人
sort who become a hideous burden to people like me.
总会成为像我这类人的可怕负担
I read books with real information.
我看书是为了追求真理
A hideous burden?
可怕的负担
I haven't seen you lift a finger since we've been here.
打我们搬来就没见你做过什么家务
I have a mind to tell your father
要不要我去告诉你爸
you who stole Aunt Alberta's sweets.
是你偷了艾伯塔姨妈的糖果
- Liar? - Really?
- 你说谎  - 是吗
Edmund, the painting!
埃德蒙,看这画
I found them under your bed.
我在你床底下发现了
And you know what? I licked every one of them!
而且我每一个都舔过了
Ew! I'm infected with you!
我会被你传染的
- What is going on here? - Lucy, do you think...
- 这是怎么了  - 露西,你觉得
It's some kind of trick.
你们在耍鬼把戏
Stop or I'll tell mother.
快停下来不然我告诉我妈
Mother!
妈妈
I'll just smash the rotten thing.
我要把这烂东西撕掉
No, Eustace! No!
尤斯提,别
We can't stop it!
我们阻止不了
Get off me! Get off!
放开我,放开
Let go of it, Eustace!
放手,尤斯提
Put it down!
把画放下
Let go!
放手
Edmund!
埃德蒙
- Eustace, swim! - What's going on?
- 尤斯提,快游  - 怎么了
Come on, move!
快躲开
keep swimming!
一直游
It's alright! I got you.
没事了,你安全了
- Caspian? - Lucy.
- 凯斯宾  - 露西
Edmund, it is Caspian.
埃德蒙,是凯斯宾
It's all right, boys. You're safe now.
没事了孩子们,你们现在安全了
Are we in Narnia?
这儿是纳尼亚吗
Yes, you are in Narnia.
是的,这里是纳尼亚
I don't wanna go. I want to go back to England!
我不想走,我要回英国
I'm going back to England!
我要回英国
Hold on.
抓好
That was thrilling!
太惊险了
How in the world do you end up here?
你们怎么在这儿
I have no idea.
我也不知道
Caspian!
凯斯宾
Edmund.
埃德蒙
It's great to see you again.
见到你真高兴
Great to see you.
我也是
Didn't you call for us?
你召唤我们了吗
No, not this time.
没有,这次没有
Well, whatever the case, I'm just glad to be here.
不管怎样,我都很高兴回来
- Now calm down, sir. - Ahh! Get that thing off me!
- 镇定  - 把这东西弄走
Reepicheep!
雷佩契普
- Your Majesty. - Hello, Reep.
- 陛下  - 你好,雷佩
- What a pleasure. - The pleasure is all mine, sir.
- 很荣幸  - 应该是我深感荣幸,阁下
But first, what to do about this,
但首先,这个歇斯底里的
this hysterical interloper?
闯入者该怎么处置
That giant rat thing just tried to claw my face off!
那个大老鼠刚才想抓我的脸
I was merely trying to expel the water from your lungs sir.
我只是想帮你把水从肺里挤出来
He talks! Did you see? Did anyone just hear that?
他说话,看到了吗,刚有人听见吗
- It just talked! - He always talks.
- 它刚说话了  - 他总说话
Actually, it's getting him to shut up that's the trick.
让他不说话才需要点魔法呢
The moment there is nothing to be said your highness,
陛下,在不需要说话的时候
I promise you I will not say it.
我保证我一句话不说
I don't know what kind of prank this is.
真不知道这是什么恶作剧
I wanna wake up right now!
但我想立马醒来
Perhaps we can throw him back?
也许我们可以把他扔回去
Edmund!
埃德蒙
I demand to know just where in the blazes am I?
快告诉我,我现在到底在哪儿
You're on the Dawn Treader. The finest ship in Narnia's navy.
这是黎明踏浪号,纳尼亚海军最棒的船
Was it something I said?
是因为我说了什么吗
- See to him, will you? - Your majesty.
- 照顾下他行吗  - 是,陛下
Men.
将士们
Behold our castaways.
看看我们刚救上来的人
Edmund the Just and Lucy the Valiant.
公正王埃德蒙和勇气女王露西
High King and Queen of Narnia.
纳尼亚的国王和女王万岁
Aslan.
阿斯兰
Look! Susan's bow and arrows.
看,苏珊的弓和箭
Lucy,
露西
My Healing Cordial and dagger.
我的神药和短剑
- oh, May I? - Of course. They are yours.
- 给我了吗  - 当然,这是你的
- Peter's sword. - Yes.
- 彼德的剑  - 是的
I looked after as promised.
我答应过代为保管的
Here. Hold it if you wish.
给,想要的话拿着
No, it's yours. Peter has given it to you.
不,这是你的,彼德给你了
I did saved this for you though.
我还帮你留着这个
Thanks.
谢谢
Since you've left, the Giants
你们走后,北方的巨人
of the North surrendered unconditionally.
无条件投降了
And we defeated the Calormen armies at the Great Desert.
我们打败了大沙漠的卡罗门军队
- There is peace across all of Narnia. - Peace?
- 纳尼亚现在一派和平景象  - 和平吗
For three years.
这三年
And have you found yourself a queen in those three years?
那这三年你有为自己找个王后吗
No. Not one to compare to your sister.
没有,都比不上你姐姐
Hang on, so there are no wars to fight
等等,现在没有战争
and no one is in trouble...
也没人有麻烦
Then, why are we here?
那我们为什么会来
That's a good question.
问得好
I have been asking myself the same thing.
我也在想这个问题
So, where are we sailing this time?
我们这次要去哪儿
To get back the throne from my uncle.
从我皇叔那儿夺回王位
He tried to kill my father's
他曾想杀掉我父亲最亲近的朋友
closest friends and most loyal supporters.
同时也是最忠实的支持者
The seven Lords of Telmar.
台尔玛七勋爵
They fled to the Lone Islands.
他们逃到了寂岛
No one has heard from them since.
从此再无音讯
So you think something has happened to them?
你觉得他们已遭不测
Well, if it has, it is my duty to find out.
如果真是这样,我有责任查清楚
What's east of the Lone Islands?
寂岛东边是什么
Uncharted waters. Things that you can barely imagine.
未知海域,难以想象之地
Tales of sea serpents and worse.
传说有海蛇或更恐怖的东西
Sea serpents?
海蛇
Alright captain, enough of your tall tales.
行了船长,你的无稽之谈到此为止
Where sky and water meet, where the waves grow ever sweet.
水天相接之地,海浪甜蜜翻涌
Doubt not, you Reepicheep.
不要怀疑,雷佩契普
To find all that you seek, there is the Utter East.
极东之外,你能找到追寻之物
Doubt not...
不要怀疑
- That's pretty! - Oh! Thank you.
- 真好听  - 谢谢
A dryad sung it to me when I was just a mouseling.
我小时候,林中仙女唱给我听的
I can't divine the meaning but I never forgotten the words.
我不明白什么意思,但歌词永生难忘
What do you think is past the Lone Islands, Reep?
雷佩,你觉得过了寂岛是什么
I've been told the furthest east one can sail
别人告诉我,航行到最东边
is to the end of the world.
是世界尽头
Aslan's country.
阿斯兰的国家
Do you really believe there is such a place?
你真相信有这么个地方吗
We have nothing if we do not believe.
如果什么都不信我们将一无所有
Do you think you can actually sail there?
那你觉得我们能航行到那儿吗
Well, there is only one way of finding that out.
只有一个办法能弄明白
Only hope one day I'd earn the right to see it.
希望我能有这个机会亲眼目睹
Your majesty.
陛下
You have grown stronger, my friend.
朋友,你变强壮了
Seems I have.
我感觉也是
Alright! Back to work.
好了,回去工作
- Your Highness. - Thank you
- 殿下  - 谢谢
Edmund, Do you think if we keep sailing
埃德蒙,你觉得如果我们一直航行
to the end of the world,
直到世界尽头
we just... tip off the edge?
我们不会从边上掉下去
Don't worry, Lu. We're long way from there.
别担心,小露,我们离那儿还远着呢
I see you're still talking nonsense, the two of you.
你们俩又在说些没用的
Are you feeling better?
感觉好点了吗
Yes, but not thanks to you.
是的,但不是因为你
It's lucky I have an iron constitution.
多亏我有钢铁般的体魄
As effervescent as ever, I see.
我看你还是一样活力四射嘛
- Found your sea legs? - Never lost them.
- 不晕船了吗  - 从没晕过
Simply dealing with the shock of things.
只是有点受惊吓而已
Mother says I have an acute disposition, due to my intelligence.
我妈说我洞察力强,因为高智商
I don't think he has "acute" anything
我觉得你毫无洞察力可言
I'll have you all know as soon as we find civilization.
到了文明社会你们就知道了
I'm contacting the British Consul.
我会联系英国大使馆
Have you all arrested for kidnapping.
告你们绑架,全抓起来
Kidnapping, is it? That's funny.
绑架是吗,真有趣
I thought we had saved your life.
我想我们救了你的小命
You held me here against my will!
你们强行把我扣留在这儿
Did I?
是吗
In, what I must say, are the most unhygienic quarters.
让我住脏透了的地下室
It's like, like a zoo down there!
那儿就像个动物园
- He's quite the complainer, isn't he? - He is just warming up.
- 他可真爱抱怨  - 这还只是热身
Land ho.
看到陆地啦
The Lone Islands. Narrow Haven's portal.
寂岛,去往东方圣境的入口
Strange. No a Narnia flag in sight.
奇怪,没看到纳尼亚国旗
But the Lone Islands have always been Narnia's.
寂岛一直属于纳尼亚
Seems suspicious.
事有蹊跷
I say we prepare a landing party.
准备一支先头登陆部队
- Drinian? - Forgive me, Your Majesty...
- 垂尼安  - 抱歉,陛下
But the chain of command starts with Prince Caspian on this ship.
但这船的最高指挥官是凯斯宾王子
- Right. - We'll use longboats.
- 好吧  - 用长船
Drinian, pick some men and come ashore.
垂尼安,派几个人登岸
Aye.
好的
Tavros.
塔若斯
Men the longboats, furl the sail and prepare to drop anchor.
准备长船,收帆准备抛描
Onward! The thrill of the unknown lies ahead.
前进,未知的刺激就在眼前
Can't we just wait till the morning?
我们就不能等到明天早上吗
There is no honor in turning away from adventure, lad.
冒险面前退缩可不好,小伙子
Listen! Where is everyone?
听,人都哪去了
- Come on, jelly legs. - I'm capable of doing it myself!
- 把手给我,哆嗦腿  - 我自己能行
And you're certain he's related by blood?
你确定你们有血缘关系吗
Reepicheep,
雷佩契普
stay here with Drinian's men and secure the place.
和垂尼安的人一起守在这里
We will head up.
我们先上去
If we don't come back by dawn,
如果明早还没回来
- send the party. - Yes, Your Majesty.
- 再派人  - 是,陛下
Yeah, looks like nobody is in.
好像这儿没人住
So do you think we should go back?
我们还是走吧
Do you want to come here and guard...something?
你想过来保护什么吗
Ah, yes. Good idea, cousin.
好的,好主意,表哥
Very..Um, logical.
非常有道理
I've got it. I've got it. Don't worry.
交给我,交给我,不用担心
I'm ready to go when you are!
需要时尽管叫我
Who are all these people?
这些人是谁
Why are they've been crossed out?
为什么他们的名字被划了
Looks like some kind of... fee?
有点像价目表
Slave traders.
奴隶买卖
Look out.
小心
Unless you want to hear this scum
除非你们想听到这个废物
squeal like a girl again,
再次像女孩一样惨叫
I would say, you should drop your weapons.
否则就放下武器
- Like a girl. - Now!
- 像女孩  - 马上
- Put it down! - Eustace
- 放下  - 尤斯提
- Put them in irons. - Come here you!
- 把他们铐起来  - 你过来
Get your hands off me.
放开我
Take these two to the market.
把这两个带去集市
Let go!
走
Send those other two to the dungeons.
另外两个关到地牢
Listen to me, you insolent fool. I am your king!
听着,无礼的蠢货,我是你们的国王
- You're gonna pay for that! - Actually...
- 你们会付出代价的  - 事实上
someone else is going to pay.
付代价的另有其人
For all of you.
你们都会被拍卖
- No! Edmund! - Lucy!
- 不,埃德蒙  - 露西
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 你还好吗  - 嗯
It is hopeless. You'll never get out.
没用的,你们出不去
- Who's there? - Nobody.
- 是谁  - 没人
Just a voice in my head.
只是我脑中回荡的声音
Lord Bern?
伯恩勋爵
That was me once. I do not no longer deserve that title anymore.
那是以前的我,现在配不上这称号了
Is he one of the seven?
他是七勋爵之一吗
Your face. You remind me of a king that I once know.
你的脸,让我想起我认识的一个国王
That man was my father.
那是我父亲
My Lord, please forgive me.
我的老天,请宽恕我
No, please.
别,请起
No!
不
Helaine!
赫兰
Mommy!
妈妈
Get back.
滚回去
Mommy!
妈妈
Stay with daddy.
跟爸爸在一起
Don't worry. I will find you!
别担心,我会找到你的
Mommy!
妈妈
- Where are they taking them? - Keep watching.
- 他们要被带去哪儿  - 继续看
- What happened? - It's a sacrifice.
- 怎么了  - 这是祭品
- Where did they go? - No one knows.
- 他们去哪了  - 没人知道
The mist was first seen in the east.
这雾最早出现在东方
Reports of fishermen and sailors disappearing out at sea.
然后就传出渔民和水手出海失踪的消息
We lords have made a pact...
所以我们几个勋爵约定
to find the source of the mist and to destroy them.
找到绿雾的源头并消灭掉
They each set sail,
我们分头起航
But none of them came back.
但没人回来
You see, If they don't sell you to the slave traders
如果他们不把你卖给奴隶贩子
You're likely to be fed to the mist.
很可能会让你喂绿雾
We have to find Lucy.
我们要尽快找到露西
Before it's too late.
不然就来不及了
- I offer 60. - I bid 80!
- 我出六十  - 我出八十
100 for the little lady.
我出一百买那个小女孩
- 120! - 150.
- 一百二  - 我出一百五
Anymore bids?
还有出价更高的吗
(已成交)
Sold!
成交
Come on, move!
快走,快走
move!
快走
And now, for this fine specimen!
大家看看,这可是上等货
Who'd kick off the bidding?
谁先出价啊
Come on now, he may not seem like much,
各位,他可能看起来不怎么样
but uh..He is strong.
可是他身强力壮
Yes, he's strong alright.
是啊,他长得是挺结实的
Smells like the rear end of a Minotaur.
闻起来跟牛头人身怪的屁股一样臭
That is an outrageous lie.
你胡说八道
I won the school hygeine award, two years running!
我连续两年获得了学校的"讲卫生"奖
Come on, someone make your bid!
来吧,大家出价吧
I'll take them off your hands.
这家伙我要了
I'll take them all out of your hands.
你的人我全都要了
For Narnia!
为纳尼亚而战
Thanks, Reep. I knew you would come.
谢谢,雷佩,我知道你会来救我的
Your Highness.
为您效劳,殿下
Grab the keys.
拿钥匙
Keys!
钥匙,接着
oh, you're a boat in a magical land.
你可是魔法大陆的船
Can't you row yourself?
你就不能自己动吗
I hope that wasn't British consul.
希望他不是英国领事
Your majesty!
国王陛下
- Your majesty! - Wait.
- 陛下  - 等一下
My wife was taken just this morning.
我的妻子今早上被人带走了
Daddy!
爸爸
I beg you, take me with you.
我求你,带我一起去吧
- I want to come. - No, Gael. Stay with your aunt.
- 我也要去  - 不盖尔,待在婶婶身旁
I am a fight sailor,
我是个水手
been on the seas my whole life.
一直生活在海上
- Of course, you must. - Thank you.
- 没问题,跟我们走吧  - 谢谢您
- But Daddy! - If I ever not come back...
- 但是爸爸  - 要是我回不来了
Now be good.
你要乖乖地听话
My king!
陛下
This was given to me by your father.
这是您父亲给我的
I hid it safely in the cave. All these years.
这些年我把它藏在洞穴里
I thought that is Narnian sword?
这是纳尼亚的剑吧
It's from your Golden Age.
这是黄金年代流传下来的剑
There are seven of those swords.
一共有七把
Gifts from Aslan to protect Narnia.
阿斯兰的礼物,来保卫纳尼亚的剑
Your father entrusted them to us.
你父亲把它们交给我们保管
Here. Take it.
拿去吧
And it may protect you.
愿它能保护您
Thank you, my Lord.
谢谢你,勋爵
And we shall find your lost sisters.
我们会找到其他的勋爵
Edmund.
埃德蒙
Dear diary. There has been extraordinary turn of event.
亲爱的日记,我的世界发生了巨大的变化
I have been abducted by my cousins
我被我的表兄妹劫持了
and set to drift in uncharted waters.
漂流在一片未知的海域
In some ridiculously looking boat.
我正在一艘外观十分可笑的船上
What's worse,
更糟的是
as I share quarters with obnoxious mouse thing,
本以为和表兄妹住一起已经够恶心了
my thought banking with my cousins was bad enough.
我现在竟然和讨厌的老鼠共处一室
So far, every person I met in this strange place
到目前为止,我在怪地方所遇到的人
suffers from the most Florit delusions,
都患有异常严重的弗洛伊德妄想症
chasing for green mists and looking for lost lords.
他们寻找着绿雾和失踪的勋爵
I can only assume this is the result of poor diet.
我只能把这归结于他们都营养不良
Everyone are barking mad.
每个人都是疯子
Cousin Edmund is no exception.
埃德蒙表哥也是
He spends every spare second rubbing that thin sword.
他一有空就擦那把薄剑
Like it's some magic lantern.
好像那是神灯一样
Poor fool clearly needs a hobby.
笨蛋必须给自己找点乐子
It is going to be magnificient.
这肯定是把好剑
Do they come in a smaller size?
这种剑有小号的吗
Peeving Marmud he's more delusional than my cousin.
讨厌的玛德蒙的妄想症比我表哥的还严重
In England we have mousetraps and that sort of things.
在英格兰我们有捕鼠器之类的东西
Speaking of food, do you think I can get any do you?
说到食物,你觉得我能搞到点吃的吗
Uh, why you talking to that bird?
你为什么和那只鸟说话
I just naturally assumed that...
我以为它当然和你一样...
He's talking to birds.
他在和鸟讲话
He is as mad as a looner that one.
他比那鸟还笨
Shoo! Go go.
走开,快走
Are you aware sir...
你知不知道
Stealing rations is a capital offense?
偷食物是死罪
Up here.
我在这儿
You.
是你啊
- Men have been killed for less. - For What?
- 程度不重也会被杀  - 什么罪
Treason and sneakiness...and general nuisances.
叛国,偷窃,还有滋扰行为
Just hand over the orange and we'll let the matter pass.
把橘子交出来,这事就算了
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
Allow me to...
请允许我
- I've had quite enough of you. - Unhand the tail.
- 我受够你了  - 把手从我尾巴上拿开
The Great Aslan himself gave me this tail.
伟大的阿斯兰赐予了我这只尾巴
No one. Repeat. No one touches the tail.
没有人,再强调一遍,没有人可以碰它
- Period. Exclamation mark! - Sorry.
- 发言完毕,打个感叹号  - 对不起
Now. I will have the orange, then I will have satisfaction.
现在,把橘子拿出来我就放你走
Puh, puh, please, please, please, um. I'm a pacifist.
别别别,求你了,我是个和平主义者
- Watch it. - Sorry.
- 当心点  - 对不起
Are you trying to run away?
你想逃跑吗
We're on a boat you know.
我们可是在船上,你知道的
Can't we just discuss this?
我们能不能不讨论这个问题
That is for stealing, that is for lying,
这是罚你偷东西,这是罚你撒谎
and that was for good measure.
这是额外的
That's the spirit! We have ourselves a duel! Catch.
就是要这气势,要决斗了,接着
Now, come on. Take your best shot.
来吧,让我看看你的本事
Is that it? Come on, boy.
你就这点本事,上呀,小子
Stop flapping your wings like a drunken pelican.
不要像醉汉似的左摇右晃
Hoist!
站直了
Keep your leg up.
把腿抬高
Yoo-hoo! Over here.
嘿嘿,我在这儿呢
On your foot. On your left, your right.
双脚要站住了,左脚,右脚
Got it? Come on. The Nimble.
懂了吗,来吧,身体灵活点
It is a dance, boy.
击剑是门舞蹈,小子
Come on now. And again.
来,再来
Oh, no.
哦,不好
And that!
吃我一腿
Look.
你们看
Gael, what are you doing here?
盖尔,你在这儿干什么
It seems that we have an extra crew member.
看来我们多了位新成员
- Welcome aboard. - Your majesty.
- 欢迎来到船上  - 女王陛下
Call me Lucy. Come on.
叫我露西就好,跟我来吧
Come on, look lovely, back to work!
好了,伙计们,回去工作了
Good match!
刚才的决斗很精彩
I will make a swordsman of you yet.
我会把你训练成一个剑客的
Yes, well...
好吧
it's the plane we look more even
要是在陆地上打话我会站的更稳
it would be an entirely different result.
到时候你肯定输
Indeed.
好吧
It looks like uninhabited.
看起来这岛上没人
If the Lords follow the mist to the east,
如果国王们寻着那雾到了东部
they would have stopped here.
他们可能会停驻在此
It could be a trap.
这可能是个圈套
Or it can held some answers.
也可能会为我们解开些谜团
Caspian?
凯斯宾
We spend the night on shore.
今晚我们在海岸歇息
Scout the island everyone.
大家侦查下这个岛
Ay, Your Majesty.
是的,陛下
Seems they have brought a pig.
这鼾声就像猪一样
This one. It's female.
选她吧,是个女的
So is this one.
她也是女的
This one reads.
她识字
Let's take her.
那就带她走
There is no escape!
你是逃不掉的
We are scary.
我们长得很可怕
What are you?
你们是谁
We are terrifying invisible beasts.
我们是青面獠牙的隐形怪物
If you could see us, you would be really intimidated.
你要是能看见我们,肯定会被吓到的
You forgot to mention that we all are very large.
你忘了说我们体型巨大
What do you want?
你们想怎么样
You'll do what we ask.
按我们说的做
She will!
她会听话的
Very clear. Well put!
说得好,简单明了
- Or what? - Or death.
- 不然呢  - 不然就杀了你
Death.Death! Death!
杀了你,杀了你
Death! Death! Death! Death!
杀了你,杀了你,杀了你
Well, I won't be much use to you when I'm dead now, would I?
我要是死了,不就没什么用了吗
I haven't thought of that.
我忽略了这点
No, you hadn't. Fair point.
对,她说得有道理
Alright. Then we'll just kill your friends!
那好吧,我们就把你的朋友杀了
- Good idea. - What do you want with me?
- 好主意  - 你们想要我做什么
You'll enter the house of the Oppressor.
进入那个暴君的城堡
- What house? - This one.
- 什么城堡  - 这个
Upstairs, you'll find the book of incantation
上楼之后你会发现一本咒语书
recite the spell that makes the unseen, seen.
朗诵那条"使隐形的都显形"的咒语
- Well put chief, well put. - Very. Yeah.
- 说的好,老大  - 说得太好了
Well, go on. We haven't got all day.
快点,我们赶时间
Remember what will happen to your friends.
记住,不照做的话你的朋友都得死
- You've been warned. - Yeah.
- 这是警告  - 是的
Right.
说得对
Why don't you do it yourself?
你们为什么不自己念
We can't read.
我们不识字
Can't write for the matter of fact.
也不会写字
- All that. - Yeah.
- 就这样  - 是的
Why didn't you just say so?
你们怎么不早说
- Beware of the opressor. - He is very aggressive!
- 小心那个暴君  - 他性情凶暴
What makes the unseen, seen.
"使隐形的都显形"
Got it? Don't forget that!
记住了吗,别忘了
Ed, wake up.
埃德,醒醒
Wake up! Look.
快醒醒,你看
Where's Lucy?
露西呢
Lucy? Lucy!
露西,露西
Everybody up!
大家快醒醒
Get up. I said.
我说快起来
- This way. - Move!
- 往这边走  - 快
(咒语书)
(牙痛治愈咒语)
(遗忘咒语)
With these words, your tongue must sew.
念了这些,你会瞠目结舌
For all around there to be snow.
周围漫布白雪
An infallible spell to make you she,
此咒语百发百中
the beauty you've always wanted to be.
让你变成心目中的美女
Susan, what's going on?
苏珊,这是怎么回事
I'm beautiful.
我真漂亮
No! Wait.
不,等等
Make me she, whom I'd agree.
把我变成心中的她
Lucy. Lucy.
露西,露西
Aslan?
是阿斯兰吗
阿斯兰吗
A spell to make the unseen, seen.
咒语,使隐形的都显形
Like the 'p' in psychology,
就像心理学中的心
the 'h' in psychiatry
和精神病学中的神
invisible ink and the truth in theology.
隐形墨水和神学中的真理
Caspian, Lucy's dagger.
凯斯宾,是露西的匕首
Stop right there or there is!
都给我站住,不许再前进了
The spell is complete.
这咒语念完了
Now all is visible.
现在万物显形
- What sort of creatures are you? - Great ones.
- 你们是什么生物  - 大怪物
With the head of a tiger and the body of...
有着老虎的头和
Um-different tiger.
另一种老虎的身体
- You don't want to mess with us! - Or what?
- 你不会想和我们杠上的  - 不然呢
Or I'll claw you to death!
不然我就会爪子撕裂你们
I'll run my touch right through you!
我会用爪一下穿透你的身体
I will crush you with my teeth.
我会用牙齿撕咬你
And I'll bite you with my fangs.
我会用我的毒牙撕咬你
You mean squash us with your fat bellies?
你是说用肥胖的肚子压死我们吗
Fatty bellies?
我们腹部肥胖吗
Or tickle us with your toes?
或是用你们的脚趾头给我们挠挠痒
What have you done with my sister, you little pip squid?
你们这些小矮人对我妹妹做了什么
- Now, calm down. - Where is she?
- 冷静点  - 她人在哪儿
- Can I tell him? - Tell him, chief.
- 我能告诉他吗  - 告诉他吧,老大
- In the mansion. - What mansion?
- 在城堡里  - 什么城堡
Oh. That mansion.
那座城堡
Now, I'm getting tired of you leaving me behind.
我讨厌总是被你们抛在后面
The thing came back.
这城堡回来了
This place is weirder and weirder.
这地方变得越来越诡异了
He's calling us weird.
他说我们诡异
Lucy!
露西
Your majesty.
陛下
Caspian and Edmund.
这是凯斯宾和埃德蒙
This is Coriakin. It's his island.
这是柯瑞金,这座岛的主人
That's what he thinks.
这只是他个人的想法
You have wronged us, magician.
魔法师,你欺负我们
I have not wronged you,
我可没欺负你们
I've made you invisible for your own protection.
我让你们隐形是为了保护你们
Protection?
保护我们吗
That's aggressive! Opressor!
你这个凶恶的暴君
I have not opressed you.
我没有压迫你们
But you could have!
但你想压迫我们的话
If you wanted to!
就能压迫我们
Be gone.
给我消失吧
What was that?
那是什么
Loot. But don't tell them.
钱,别告诉他们
- What were those things? - Dufflepuds.
- 那是什么生物  - 蹩脚仙
Of course. Silly me.
当然,我怎么傻了
What did you mean when you said
你说你让他们隐形是为了保护他们
you made them invisible for their own good?
这话是什么意思
It seems to be the easiest way to protect them.
在我看来,那是保护他们不受恶魔伤害
From the evil.
最简单的方法
You mean the mist?
你是指那绿雾吗
I mean what lies behind the mist.
我是指绿雾后面的东西
It's quite beautiful.
这可真漂亮
I mean for a made belived map and a made believed world.
我是说这图和这个世界一样活灵活现
There is the source of your problems.
这里是问题的根源
The Dark Island.
黑暗之岛
A place where evil lurks.
恶魔藏匿之地
It can take any form.
恶魔可以化身成任何形式
It can make your darkest dreams come true.
它可以实现你最黑暗的梦想
It seeks to corrupt all goodness
它要腐化世间的一切善
Steal the lights from this world.
盗取世界上所有的光明
How do we stop it?
我们怎样才能阻止它
You must break its spell.
你们必须破除咒语
That sword you carry,
你带着的那把剑
there are six others.
另外还有六把
- Have you seen them? - Yes.
- 你见过那六把剑吗  - 是的
The six lords, they passed through here?
六位勋爵,他们都来过这儿吗
Indeed.
是的
Where are they heading?
他们去哪儿了
Where I've sent them.
去了我送他们去的地方
Break the spell.
要破除咒语
You must follow the Blue Star...
你必须要跟随蓝星
to Ramandu's Island.
到达拉曼杜所在的星辰岛
There the seven swords must be laid at Aslan's table.
七把剑必须都放在阿斯兰的餐桌上
Only then can the truly magical power be released.
只能那样才能释放出真正的法力
But beware.
但是要小心
You will all about to be tested.
你们都要经受考验
Tested?
考验
Until you lay down the seventh sword,
你们放下最后一把剑之前
evil has the upper hand.
恶魔都会主宰着局面
It will do everything in it's power to tempt you.
它会用尽一切手段来诱惑你们
Be strong...
要意志坚定
Don't fall to temptations.
不要被诱惑所迷
To defeat the darkness out there
要想战胜邪恶势力
you must defeat the darkness inside yourself.
你必须先战胜自己内心的阴暗
For reasons beyond my comprehension
因为一些我无法理解的原由
We have taken the advice from the senile old coup.
我们采纳了那个老头愚蠢的建议
who doesn't possess a razor,
他不刮胡子
and walks around on a dressing gown.
而且还一直穿着长袍
So we're back in the bathtub
现在,我们又回到这浴缸里
and and lost in the tempest. Brilliant!
迷失在暴风雨中,好极了
14 days of being tossed like a pancake,
像平锅上的煎饼一样颠了十四天
not the slightest sight of land.
我们仍看不见陆地
The only consolation is
唯一的慰藉便是
that everyone is finally as miserable as I am.
所有人最终都变得和我一样沮丧
Except for that show-off talking rat.
除了那只爱卖弄会说话的老鼠
He is one of the annoying glass is always half full part.
他对任何事都保持令人厌恶的乐观态度
So, we're stuck here...
目前我们滞留在这儿
with half rations,
补给只剩一半
we have food and water for two more weeks maximum.
食物和水最多维持两周
This is your last chance to turn back, your majesty.
这是最后的改变主意的机会了,陛下
There is no guarantee that we will spot the blue star anytime soon.
近期内不一定能看到蓝星
Not in this storm.
至少暴风雨中可不行
Needle in a haystack trying to find this remoteness place.
寻找这片陌土犹如海底捞针
We can sail way past and knocked to the end of world.
我们很可能航行过头最后到了世界尽头
We can be eaten by a sea serpent.
我们可能会被海蛇活活吃掉
You'll see when the men are getting nervous.
等船员们惊慌失措时就麻烦了
These are strange seas we are sailing
这片海域很诡异
the lights that which i've never seen before.
海面泛出的光色我从没见过
Then perhaps captain, you'd love to be the one
船长,那么您一定很愿意
to explain to Mr. Rince that we're abandoning
亲自告知林斯先生我们打算放弃
the search for his families?
搜救她妻子
I'll get back to it.
我会继续努力
Just a word of warning,
只是给您提个醒
the seas can play nasty tricks on a crew mind.
海洋会让水手的心里充满惶恐
Very nasty.
惶恐万分
Transform my reflection,
改变我之容貌
cast into affection.
让人心生爱慕
lashes, lips and complexion.
睫毛,嘴唇,面容
Let me feel whom I agree,
让我变成心中的她
hold more beauty over me.
让我更加美丽
Ladies and Gentlemen, Ms. Pevensie.
女士们先生们,欢迎佩文西小姐
Edmund?
埃德蒙
You look beautiful, Sister.
姐姐,你真漂亮
As always.
一直都那么美
Peter!
彼德
Excuse me Miss, Can I get a photo?
打扰一下小姐,介意照张相吗
Mother's gonne love this,
妈妈一定喜欢这样照片
all her children in one picture.
她三个儿女的合影
Smile!
笑一笑
Hang on. Where am I?
等等,这是哪儿
I mean where's Lucy?
我是说露西怎么没来
Lucy, who's Lucy?
露西,露西是谁
Susan, what's wrong?
苏珊,你怎么了
Come on now Miss. A nice big smile!
小姐看这里,笑一下
Edmund, I'm not sure about this. I think I want to go back.
埃德蒙,我不想这样,我想回去
Go back where?
回哪里
To Narnia!
回到纳尼亚去
What is Narnia?
纳尼亚是哪里
What's going on?
这到底是怎么回事
Stop this!
别照
Lucy.
露西
Aslan?
阿斯兰
What have you done, child?
孩子,你做了什么
I don't know, but that was awful.
我也不知道,但感觉糟透了
But you chose it, Lucy.
但你那是你选的,露西
I didn't mean to choose all that.
我并没打算那么做
I just wanted to be as beautiful like Susan.
我只不过是希望和苏珊一样美
That's all
只是这些
You wished yourself away, and with it, much more.
你希望自己消失掉,一发不可收拾
Your brothers and sisters
如果没有你
wouldn't know Narnia without you, Lucy.
他们不会意识到纳尼亚的存在,露西
You discovered it first, remember?
你是第一个发现这里的,还记得吗
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
You doubt your value, don't run from who you are.
不要怀疑自己的价值,不要迷失自我
Aslan!
阿斯兰
Father. Father.
父皇,父皇
Edmund. Edmund.
埃德蒙,埃德蒙
Come with me. Join me.
跟我来吧,跟我走
Edmund?
埃德蒙
Lucy.
露西
I can't sleep.
我睡不着
Let me guess. Bad dreams?
我猜猜,又做噩梦了吗
So either we're all going mad,
看来要不我们全疯了
or something is playing with our minds.
要不就是有东西在扰乱我们的意志
I doubt the Lords stopped here, my liege.
我想勋爵们没来过这儿,陛下
There is no sign of anything living.
这儿毫无生命的迹象
Right. Well, once you have got on shore,
没错,上岸后
take your men for food and water.
带上你的人去寻找补给
The three of us will look for clues.
我们三人去找线索
Hang on, You mean the four of us?
等等,把我也算上吧
Come on, please don't send me back to the rat.
求你了,别让我和那只老鼠待一起
I heard that!
我听到了
Big ears.
耳朵真灵
I heard that too.
这句我也听到了
Look. We not the first on the island.
看,这儿有人迹
The Lords?
勋爵们吗
Could be.
也许吧
What do you think could be down there?
你觉得这下面会有什么
Let's find out.
去看看吧
What is that?
那是什么
I don't know. Looks like some kind of a gold statue.
不清楚,看上去像是一尊金像
He must have fallen in.
他一定是失足坠入水中的
Poor man.
可怜的人
You mean, poor Lord.
他是勋爵
The crust of Lord rest in him.
愿他的灵魂得以安息
And his sword.
看,他的剑
We need it.
我们需要它
Be careful.
小心
Your sword hasn't turn to gold.
你的剑没有化作金子
Both swords are magical.
两把剑都蕴藏魔力
He mustn't have known what hit him.
他一定不知道是什么袭击了他
Maybe, or maybe He was onto something.
也许吧,但他也可能是来寻觅什么的
What are you talking about?
什么意思
What are you staring at?
你在看什么
Whoever has access to this pool,
到过这水池的人
could be the most powerful person in the world.
可以主宰整个世界
Lucy, we'll be so rich
露西,我们非常富有
no one can tell us what to do,
没人能命令我们做什么
or who to live with.
或寄宿在谁哪儿
You can't take anything out of Narnia, Edmund.
纳尼亚的东西你一样也带不走,埃德蒙
Says who?
谁说的
I do.
我说的
I am not your subject.
我不是你的仆从
You have been waiting for this, haven't you?
你一直盼着这一刻,不是吗
To challenge me. You doubt my leadership!
你一直想挑战我,你怀疑我的领导能力
You doubt yourself.
你自己都没信心
You're a child.
你还是个孩子
And you're a spineless sap.
你是个没骨气的窝囊货
Edmund?
埃德蒙
I'm tired of playing second fiddle...
我厌倦当副手的日子
First it was Peter, and now it's you.
之前是彼德,现在又换成了你
You know I am braver than both of you.
你清楚我比你们两个都勇猛
Why did you get Peter's sword?
你凭什么拥有彼德的剑
I deserve a kingdom of my own!
我才配拥有自己的国度
I deserve to rule!
我才配当国王
If you think you're so brave...
如果你认为自己真的那么勇敢
prove it!
那就证明给我看
No! Stop it!
不,住手
Both of you. Look at yourselves.
都住手,看看你们自己
Can't you see what's happenning?
难道你们没发觉吗
This place has tempted you.
这地方在考验你们
It is bewitching you.
是在蛊惑你们
This is exactly what Coriakin is talking about.
这不正如柯瑞金所讲的吗
Let's just get outta here.
我们离开这里吧
Oh yes, follow the imaginary blue star,
很好,顺着蓝星的指引
to the island of Rabandoedoe...
去什么星辰岛
Like the seven steak knives on the table of a talking lion.
会说话的狮子餐桌上的七把剑什么的
Nonsense.
全是胡扯
What is that?
那是什么
I must be dead.
我一定是死了
You are definitely dead.
你确实是死了
You wouldn't be needing that one wont you.
你不会需要这个的
Finally, a favorable turn of events.
最终,事情终于出现好转了
What foods did you found?
找到什么能吃的了吗
It is volcanic, My majesty. Not much grows.
这儿是火山地质,物种不多,陛下
Where is Eustace?
尤斯提哪去了
I believe he's out not helping us loading the boats.
他肯定没留下来帮我们装货
Eustace!
尤斯提
I have got a bad feeling.
我有不好的预感
I'm going to find him.
我去找他
I'll come with you.
我也一起去
Eustace?
尤斯提
Treasure.
宝藏
Trouble.
麻烦
Eustace's.
尤斯提的
No.
不
I'm sorry.
我很遗憾
He was just a boy.
他还是个孩子
I never should have left him.
我不该丢下他不管
What could have happened to him?
他会发生什么事
In this place? Anything.
这里吗,一切皆有可能
And he wasn't the first.
而且他不是第一个
It's Lord Octesian.
这是巫大仙勋爵
We should find this... sword.
我们得找到他的剑
What was that?
那是什么
Is it the volcano?
火山爆发了吗
Oh no, that's not a volcano. All hands on deck.
不,那不是火山,全员集合
Archers, arm yourselves!
弓箭手,准备御敌
Take your positions and wait for my command.
坚守阵地,听候发令
What is it doing?
它想干什么
Fire!
发射
He will break the mast.
他会毁掉桅杆的
Right.
好吧
Hold your positions.
坚守阵地
Fire!
发射
Edmund!
埃德蒙
Lucy.
露西
(我是尤斯提)
You've got to be joking!
开玩笑的吧
He must have been tempted by the treasure.
他一定是被那些宝藏诱惑了
Everyone knows that the dragon's treasure is enchanted.
大家都知道龙的宝藏有魔力
Well, anyone from here.
我是说这里的人都知道
Is there any way to change him back?
有什么方法能让他复原吗
Not that I know of.
我可不知道
Aunt Alberta will not be pleased.
艾伯塔舅舅一定会发怒的
Sorry about the hand, oh boy.
伙计,刺伤你手的事我很抱歉
I can be a little over zealous sometimes.
有时我是有些过火
The boats are ready, sire.
一切准备就绪了,先生
We can not leave him.
我们不能把它丢下
Well, we can't bring him on board, Your Majesty.
但我们也无法让他上船,陛下
You and others take one boat back.
你和其他人先坐船回去
The rest of us stay here until morning.
我们留在这里过夜
and work out what to do.
我们得想想办法
But you have no provisions.
但您没有补给
And no means of staying warm, My Majesty
也没有保暖的措施,陛下
And you were saying?
你刚刚说什么
I've never seen these constellation before.
从没见过这么美丽的星空
Me neither.
我也没
We are long way from home.
我们远离家乡
When I was a boy I used to imagine sailing to the end of the world.
儿时我常幻想能航行至世界的尽头
To find my father there.
在那里找到我父亲
Maybe you will.
也许你会实现的
I miss my mommy.
我想妈妈了
I miss mine too.
我也是
Don't worry, you'll see her again.
别担心,你们一定会再见的
How do you know?
你怎么知道的
You just have to have faith about these things.
你要对此有信心
Aslan will help us.
阿斯兰会帮助我们的
But Aslan could have stop her from being taken.
但阿斯兰没能阻止他们抓走我妈妈
We'll find her, I promise.
我们会找到她的,我保证
Somehow.
一定会的
Trouble sleeping?
睡不着吗
Now now, all is not lost as it seems.
事情并不是你想象得那么糟糕
I'll stay up with you if you wish. To keep you company.
你不介意的话,我会在这陪着你
You didn't even believe in dragons this morning.
今早你一定还不相信这世上有龙
You know, extraordinary things only happen to extraordinary people.
非凡的事只发生在非凡的人身上
Maybe it's a sign!
也许这是个暗示
That you've got an extraordinary destiny
暗示着你将有非凡的命运
Something greater than you could have imagine.
甚至非凡得超乎你的想象
I can tell you
如果你想听
one or two of my adventures if you like,
我可以跟你分享些我的冒险经历
just past the time.
打发打发时间嘛
Believe it or not,
信不信由你
you are not the first dragon I've encountered.
我以前就见过飞龙
Many years ago, too many that I care to imagine.
记不得是多久之前了
I was with a band of pirates
我是海盗中的一员
and I met another dragon.
我们遭遇了一条飞龙
Much fierce than you.
那比你可凶猛多了
Lucy, wake up.
露西,醒醒
Look.
快看
The Blue Star.
是蓝星
- Everybody. - What?
- 大家快看  - 什么
Everybody, wake up. It is the blue star.
大家快醒醒,是蓝星
Come on, budy, wake up.
快醒醒伙计
Pull.
拉
Put your strokes in there, lads! Pull!
用桨划过去,兄弟们,拉
The wind has left.
风停了
So how do we get to Ramandu Island now then?
那我们怎么才能到达星辰岛
My guess is something doesn't want us to get there.
我觉得是什么东西试图阻止我们
Pull.
拉
If I'm getting hungrier, I'm gonna eat that dragon!
我要是饿急了,我就吃了那条龙
Don't worry, Eustace, they will to deal with me first.
别担心,尤斯提,想吃你他们得先问问我
If we don't get to landfall by tonight,
晚上之前不能登陆的话
they might as well eat that...
真说不准吃了他
What are we hitting?
我们撞到什么了
Eustace, that's brilliant!
尤斯提,你真棒
En route!
上路啦
We can't be sure that
不清楚其他几位勋爵
the other Lords even made it to Ramandu's Island.
是否成功到了星辰岛
You got us there!
你成功了
What did I tell you? Eustace, you're extraordinary!
我说什么来着,尤斯提你是非凡的
Wait.
等等
Lord Revilian.
雷维林勋爵
Lord Mavramorn.
马拉蒙勋爵
Lord Argoz.
阿格茲勋爵
He's breathing!
他还有呼吸
So are they.
他们也都活着
They're under the spell.
他们被诅咒了
It's the food!
食物有诅咒
Hey, it's the stone knife. This is Aslan's table!
看啊,是石刀,这是阿斯兰的餐桌
The swords.
剑
Let me take it.
让我来
That's six.
六把
We're missing one.
还少一把
Look!
快看
Travellers of Narnia
纳尼亚的旅行者们
Welcome.
欢迎你们
Arise!
请起
Are you not hungry?
你们都不饿吗
Who are you?
你是谁
I am Lilliandil.
我是莉莉安迪尔
Daughter of Ramandu.
星宿拉曼杜之女
I am your guide.
我是你们的向导
You're a star.
你是蓝星
You're most beautiful.
你真是美极了
If it is a distraction for you,
如果这分散了你的注意力
- I can change forms. - No.
- 我可以换个外形  - 不
Please.
请吧
The food is for you.
食物是为你们准备的
There is enough for all
只要是受欢迎的人
who are welcome at Aslan's table.
阿斯兰的餐桌都会让他尽情享用
Always. Help yourselves.
永远,请便吧
Wait.
等等
What happened to them?
他们怎么了
These poor men were half mad by the time they reached our shores.
这些可怜人来的时候就神志不清
They threatened each other with violence.
他们互相残杀
Violence is forbidden at the table of Aslan.
在阿斯兰的桌前是禁止暴力的
So they were sent to sleep.
所以他们被施了睡眠咒
Will they ever awake?
他们会醒过来吗
When all is put right.
当一切都恢复平静
Come. There is little time.
过来,没有时间了
The Magician Coriakin told you of Dark Island?
魔法师柯瑞金告诉你们黑暗岛了吗
Yes.
是的
For long the evil will be unstoppable.
最终恶魔将会势不可挡
Coriakin said, to break the spell,
柯瑞金说,如果要打破魔咒
we need the seventh sword on the Aslan's table.
我们需要把第七把剑放到阿斯兰的餐桌上
- He speaks the truth. - But we found only six.
- 他说得对  - 但是我们只找到了六把
Do you know where the seventh is?
你知道第七把在哪儿吗
In there.
在那里
You will need great courage.
你们需要很大的勇气
Now, don't waste your time.
现在别再浪费时间了
How we meet again?
我们怎样才能再见面
Goodbye.
再见
So what do you think it's in there?
你们觉得那里有什么
Our worst nightmares.
我们最恐怖的梦魇
Our darkest wishes.
我们最邪恶的欲望
Pure evil.
真正的恶魔
Tavros, unlock the armory
塔若斯,打开装备库
My Lord.
是的,阁下
Archers, prepare yourselves.
弓箭手,准备
Dock the lanterns.
向目标靠近
Let's get ready.
我们去准备一下
When I grow up, I want to be just like you.
希望我长大后能像你一样
When you grow up,
等你长大了
you should be just like you.
你应该做你自己
If case we don't get through,
如果我们失败了
whatever this is...
不管怎样...
I want you to know I think of you as my brother.
我想让你知道,我视你为兄弟
Me too.
我也是
You gave up your sword.
你放弃了你的剑
It was not mine to keep.
它不属于我
Use this.
用这把
But it is...
但它是...
Peter would like you to have it.
彼德会希望你用它的
Here it is, my friend.
就是那儿,我的朋友
The battle awaits.
战斗就在眼前
Eustace, no. Wait.
尤斯提,不,等等
Eustace, stop
尤斯提,停下来
Stop.
停
I will not accept surrender.
我不接受放弃
A true warrior does not flight out of fear.
真正的勇士不会临阵脱逃
Look at me when I'm talking to you.
看着我,我在跟你说话
I'm a mouse. You a dragon.
我是只老鼠,你是一只龙
You have a skin like leather. You breathe fire.
你有坚硬的皮肤,你会喷火
Come on, let's meet our destiny.
来吧,让我们面对我们的命运
No matter what happens here.
无论这里发生什么
every soul standing before me,
每个站在我面前的人
has earned a place on the Dawn Treader.
都是黎明踏浪号的一员
Together we traveled far.
我们曾一起探险远行
Together, we have faced diversity. Together...
我们曾一起历经磨难
we can do it again.
我们会一起再次胜利
So now is not the time
所以现在不应该
to fall in fears and temptations. Be strong!
害怕或受到诱惑,坚强起来
Never give in.
永不放弃
Our world,
这就是我们的世界
our Narnian lives depend on it.
纳尼亚的精神
Think of the lost souls we are here to save.
想想我们要去拯救的灵魂
Think of Aslan.
想想阿斯兰
- Think of Narnia. - For Narnia!
- 想想纳尼亚  - 为纳尼亚而战
For Narnia!
为纳尼亚而战
Helene?
伊莲
We can't see a thing.
我们什么也看不见
The fog is too thick.
雾太浓了
You're a great disappointment to me.
你真让我失望
You call yourself my son?
你也配做我的儿子吗
And act like a king.
还装模作样的像个国王
Edmund.
埃德蒙
Come with me.
跟我来
Be my king.
做我的国王
- I let you rule. - Go away.
- 我让你统治  - 滚开
You're dead.
你已经死了
You can never kill me.
你永远杀不死我
I will always be alive in your mind, silly boy.
我永远活在你的意识里,傻孩子
- No! - Edmund?
- 不  - 埃德蒙
Are you alright?
你还好吗
Yeah!
是的
Keep away!
滚远点
Who's there?
谁在那儿
- Will we not fear you! - Not, are you?
- 我们不害怕你  - 真的吗
- Keep away! - We do not leave.
- 滚远点  - 我们不会离开
You will not defeat me.
你们打不倒我
Caspian
凯斯宾
Caspian, the sword!
凯斯宾,那把剑
Lord Rhoop.
路普勋爵
You cannot own me!
你抓不住我
Stand down.
撤下
Let's get him onboard, quickly!
让他上船,快
Be calm my Lord.
冷静点,勋爵
Off me, demons!
别碰我,恶魔们
No, my Lord
不,勋爵
We're not here to hurt you. I am your king.
我们不会伤害你,我是你的国王
Caspian.
凯斯宾
My Lord.
我的殿下
You should not have come. There is no way out of here.
您不应该来这里, 这里没有出路
Quickly turn this ship about before it is too late.
趁现在不晚,赶快调转船头
We have the sword. Let's go!
我们拿到剑了,快走
Let's turn this ship around.
快点掉头
All on you, my majesty.
遵命,陛下
Do not think.
不要想什么
Do not let it know your fears,
不要让它知道你们的恐惧
or it will become them!
否则恐惧会成真
- Oh no. - Edmund.
- 不  - 埃德蒙
- What did you just think of? - I'm sorry.
- 你刚刚想什么了  - 对不起
Look!
看
What is that?
那是什么
It's too late!
太晚了
Get on the boat. Just get on the boat.
开船啊,快开船
Gael.
盖尔
Come, walk.
过来,走
Don't let me down. No fear. No retreats.
别让我失望,不害怕,不撤退
For Narnia! Take that.
为纳尼亚而战,尝尝这个
And that.
还有这个
Eustace, hang on!
尤斯提,坚持住
- I'll kill it. - No, the sword!
- 我要杀了它  - 不,剑
The sword!
那把剑
Eustace!
尤斯提
Come back.
回来
We are doomed. Doomed!
我们难逃一死,难逃一死
- Turn this ship about. - Stop him.
- 调转船头  - 阻止他
Let's stop him.
快阻止他
Rowers. To your rowing position.
划船手,各就各位
- Forward at double speed. - Aslan, please help us.
- 全速前进  - 阿斯兰,请帮助我们
Pull.
拉
Pull!
Where are you?
你在哪儿
You must stay here until someone comes and get you!
在别人来救你之前,待在这儿别动
Ed!
埃德
Ed! We run the serpent, smash him on the rocks.
埃德,我们引着海蛇,把它撞到石头上
Stay on the port, I will keep it on the ground.
你来掌舵,我来掩护
Look out!
小心
Pull!
拉
Try to kill me, come on! Come on here.
来杀我啊,来啊,来啊
- No! - Edmund.
- 不  - 埃德蒙
I'm still here.
我还在这儿
Brace yourselves!
站稳了
Move!
快跑
We can beat this.
我们能打败它
- We must get closer. - Everybody to the main deck.
- 我们得靠的更近  - 所有人去甲板上
Ready the hard lance.
长矛手准备
I want everyone here.
所有人都过来
Ready...
准备
now!
扔
Put his head down!
把他的头拉下来
Heave!
抛
Edmund!
埃德蒙!
What are you trying to prove, Edmund?
你在试着证明什么吗,埃德蒙
That you are a man?
证明你是个男子汉吗
Do it!
拉
I can make you that.
我能助你一臂之力
I can make you my king.
我可以让你成为我的国王
Just take my hand.
抓住我的手
Just give it here.
把手给我就行
Do it!
杀死它
Come on!
来啊
No!
不
The spell, it has lifted.
咒语,被解除了
Edmund,
埃德蒙
Caspian, Look!
凯斯宾,看
Narnians!
是纳尼亚人
纳尼亚人
- Mommy! - Helene.
- 妈妈  - 伊莲
Rince, Gael.
林斯,盖尔
Mommy.
妈妈
Let's have them onboard, clear the decks.
清理甲板,让他们上船
We did it, I knew we would.
我们成功了,我知道我们会成功的
- It wasn't just us. - You mean?
- 不只是我们  - 你是说
I'm here, Lucy.
我在这儿,露西
Over here!
这边
Here, Lucy. I'm in the water. Lucy
这边,露西,我在水里,露西
Eustace!
尤斯提
I am a boy again. I am a boy!
我又变回人了,变成人了
Eustace! I see your wings have been clipped.
尤斯提,我看到你的翅膀消失了
Where sky and water meet. Where the waves grow ever sweet.
水天相接之地,海浪甜蜜翻涌
It's sweet!
这水是甜的
Look.
看
Look!
Aslan's country.
阿斯兰的国家
We must have be close.
我们肯定很接近了
Well, we've come so far.
我们走了这么远
So what was it like? When Aslan changed you back?
阿斯兰把你变回来时,你感觉如何
No matter how hard I tried, I just couldn't do it myself.
无论我怎么努力,我都动不了
Then he came towards me. It was sort of hurt, but...
然后他走过来,有点疼,但是...
It was good pay.
很值得
Like when you pull a sword from your foot.
就像把剑从脚里拔出来
Being a dragon wasn't all bad.
做只龙也不坏
I mean I was a better dragon than a boy, really.
至少我做龙时比做人更好
I'm so sorry for being such a sob.
抱歉,我总是抱怨
It's okay Eustace. You were a pretty good dragon.
没关系,尤斯提,你曾是条好龙
My friends, we've arrived
朋友们,我们到了
Aslan.
阿斯兰
Welcome, children. You have done well.
欢迎,孩子们,你们干得不错
Very well indeed.
确实很棒
You have come far.
你们从遥远的地方而来
Now your journey is at it's end.
现在你们的旅程结束了
Is this your country?
这是您的国家吗
No, my country lies beyond.
不,我的国家在后面
Is my father in your country?
我的父亲在您的国家吗
You can only find that out on yourself, my son.
你需要自己去寻找,我的孩子
But you should know that if you continue, there is no return.
但你要知道一旦你继续,就无法回头
You not going?
你不去吗
Can't imagine my father would be very proud
如果我放弃了父亲为之牺牲的国度
that I gave up what he died for.
父皇肯定会很生气
I spent too long wanting what
我花了太长时间追寻
have been taken from me but not what was given.
我失去的东西,而不是我得到的
I was given a kingdom.
我得到了王国
People.
人民
I promise to be a better king.
我保证会成为一位好国王
You already are.
你已经是了
Children.
孩子们
I think perhaps it's time we went home actually then?
我想我们是时间回家了
- I thought you loved it here? - I do!
- 我以为你喜欢这里  - 确实
But I love home and our family as well!
但是我也爱故乡和家人
They need us.
他们需要我们
Your eminence, ever since I can remember,
阁下,从我记事起
I've dreamt of seeing your country
我就盼望着能见识您的国家
I have had many great adventures in this world,
我在这个世界经历了很多冒险
but nothing has dampen that yearning.
但是这个愿望始终没有泯灭
I know I'm hardly worthy, but with your permission...
我知道我不配,但是希望您能允许...
I'd lay down my sword for the joy of
我会欣然放下剑
seeing your country with my own eyes.
亲眼去见识您的国家
My country was made for noble hearts such as yours.
我的国度为你们这种高尚之心而建
No matter how small that can be.
无论你多么矮小
- Your majesty. - Nobody deserves it more.
- 陛下  - 没人比你更适合了
It's true.
没错
May I?
我可以吗
Well, I suppose...just this..
我想...就这样了...
Goodbye, Lucy.
再见,露西
Don't cry.
别哭
I don't understand.
我不明白
When will I see you again?
什么时候我还能见到你
What a magnificent puzzle you are.
你真是一个谜
And a true hero.
也是一个英雄
It has been my honor to fight beside
能和你并肩作战是我的荣幸
such a brave warrior.
你是真正的勇士
And a great friend.
真正的好朋友
I won't be needing this.
我不再需要这个了
This is our last time here, isn't it?
这是我们最后一次来这里了吧
Yes.
是的
You have grown up, my dear one.
你已经长大了,亲爱的
Just like Peter and Susan.
就像彼德和苏珊
Will you visit us in our world?
你会来我们的世界看我们吗
I shall be watching you always.
我始终都在注视着你们
- How? - In your world...
- 怎么会  - 在你们的世界...
I have another name. You must learn to know me by it.
我有另外一个名字,你们会由此找到我
That was the very reason you were brought to Narnia.
这也是你们来到纳尼亚的原因
That by knowing me here for a little,
在这里对我多一些了解
You'll know me better there.
在那边你能更好地了解我
Will we meet again?
我们还会再见吗
Yes, dear one. One day.
是的,亲爱的,总有一天
You are closest to me I have as family.
你们就像我的家人一样
And that includes you, Eustace.
也包括你,尤斯提
Thank you.
谢谢
Will I come back?
我还会回来吗
Narnia may yet of need of you.
纳尼亚也许还会需要你
Eustace!
尤斯提
Eustace! What are you doing up there?
尤斯提,你在上面干什么呢
Jill drops in for a visit.
姬兒来看你了
We spoke often of Narnia in the days that follow.
之后的一段时间我们总谈论纳尼亚
And when all my cousins have left.
直到他们离开
After the war ended...
战争结束之后...
I missed them with all my heart.
我十分想念他们
As I know all Narnians will miss them
我想纳尼亚人也会想念他们的
Till the end of time.
直到永远